Guide to the Zelda Fichandler papers, 1950-2000
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Zelda Fichandler papers
1950-2000
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Zelda Fichandler
C0010
104.5 linear ft.; 209 boxes
This collection contains the working and personal papers of Zelda Fichandler. Items include correspondence regarding productions, staff, finances, playwrights and actors as well as personal matters and speeches and remarks given by Zelda.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Arena Stage in 2000.
Historical Information
Zelda Fichandler was the Founding Director of Arena Stage in Washington, D.C. and its primary artistic force from 1950-1990. Her history-making example, force of personality, and eloquence as a speaker and writer have made her a leading national figure in the performing arts and Arena Stage a model for scores of cultural institutions established around the country. Zelda's personal vision for theatre has had a transforming effect on the entire field, switching the axis from Broadway to the rest of the nation in the production of new work. She is considered a parent of the regional theatre in America.
Zelda embraced a vast sweep of dramatic literature which reverberated through the commercial and non-commercial theatre world and into film and television. She directed many of Arena's productions including Mrs. Klein, Uncle Vanya, The Three Sisters, Death of a Salesman, An Enemy of the People, Six Characters in Search of an Author, and A Doll House; and the American premieres of new Eastern European works, Duck Hunting, The Ascent of Mt. Fuji, and Screenplay. Arena Stage was the first American theatre company, sponsored by the State Department, to tour the then-Soviet Union. Her Inherit the Wind played in Moscow and St. Petersburg in 1973, the company performed her After the Fall at the 1980 Hong Kong Arts Festival, and in 1987, her production of The Crucible appeared at the Israel Festival in Jerusalem. As a producer, Zelda nurtured all of Arena's plays, making a home for important European playwrights like Brecht, Frisch, Ionesco, Mrozek, and Orkeny, alongside significant American revivals of works by Albee, Miller, Williams, O'Neill, Thornton Wilder, Kaufman and Hart and classics by Shakespeare, Shaw, Moliere, Ibsen, and others. Broadway, too, has felt the impact of Zelda's work, especially with the development of new plays. The Great White Hope, Indians, Moonchildren, Pueblo, A History of the American Film, The Madness of God, Raisin, and K2 all started at Arena Stage. She left the artistic leadership of Arena in 1991 to her close associate, Douglas C. Wager. Zelda also made Arena the theatre of the "second chance," where plays like Summer of the 17th Doll, Saturday, Sunday, Monday, and The Comedians found life after commercial failure in New York.
Zelda's concern for the development of young actors led her, in 1984, to take on, in addition, the role of Chair of the Graduate Acting Program and Master Teacher of Acting and Directing at New York University's Tisch School of the Arts, a position which she continues to fill. Graduates of this premier program now occupy leading positions in film, television, and the stage, winning top awards in the various media. From 1991 through 1994, she also served as the Artistic Director of The Acting Company, a young company of actors that tours a classical repertory throughout America. The link between professional theatre and training is important to Zelda as a means "to attract young people to the benefits of company work and to train them to perform in the broadest repertory." The idea of "company" has animated her work since the beginning, and her goal now is to establish in New York an acting company composed primarily of graduates from the Graduate Acting Program. Many agents, casting directors, and stage directors consider the Program at Tisch to be the most innovative and creative in the country.
Zelda has received the National Medal of the Arts, awarded in 1997 by President Clinton, the Common Wealth Award for distinguished service to the dramatic arts, The Brandeis University Creative Arts award, The Acting Company's John Houseman Award for commitment to the development of young American actors, the Margo Jones Award for the production of new plays, Washingtonian of the Year Award, the Ortho 21st Century Women Trailblazer Award, and the Society for Stage Directors and Choreographers George Abbott Award. The New York commercial theatre world awarded Zelda and Arena Stage the Antoinette Perry or 'Tony' Award in 1976, the first to be given to a company outside New York. In 1999 she was inducted into the Theatre Hall of Fame, making her the first artistic leader outside of New York to receive this honor.
Scope and Content
This collection contains the working and personal papers of Zelda Fichandler. Items include correspondence regarding productions, staff, finances, playwrights and actors as well as personal matters and speeches and remarks given by Zelda.
The bulk of collection contains Zelda's research of plays including; playbills and programs, reviews, articles, correspondence regarding plays and their past productions and audience response letters. Items of note include many papers regarding the original production of The Great White Hope, and information regarding Arena Stages tour of Russia in 1973.
Arrangement
Organized by folder.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives holds the Arena Stage records.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Arena Stage (Organization: Washington, D.C.)
Subjects:
Theater--Washington (D.C.)
Contents List
- Zelda Fichandler papers
  - correspondence; American Directors Institute (mid 1980's) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - correspondence and info; American Conservatory Theatre (mid 1980's) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - correspondence; American College Theater festival, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - correspondence; Mr. Benny Ambush, producing director at the Oakland Ensemble Theatre (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - correspondence; Benny Ambush of the Arena Stage on Black Audiance development, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - correspondence: Alton Jones Foundation (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - correspondence: The American Center for the Alexander Technique (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - letter of recommendation to NYU for Jason Alexander (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - correspondence: Jane Alexander (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - correspondence: Bob Alexander (1970's - 1990's) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - lose material, Living Stage (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - correspondence: The Ford Foundatioon (1959-early 60's) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - correspondence: The Ford Foundation, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1985-1986 season financial information (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - misc. Arena Stage progarms and brochures (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1984-1985 annual report and misc. programs (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1986-1987 financial statements (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - outline to speeches and misc. items (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - box office sales records for "She Stoops to Conquer", and "Of Mice and Men" (1950's) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - misc. speeches and plannng documents (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - misc. speech materials (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - production lists and critical comments, late 1970's (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - draft: "The Arena Stage Story:1950-1980" (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - employee guidelines and handbook (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - info on "An Acting Workshop" (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - info on the Actors Lab (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Actors letters: 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - acupuncture (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Stella Adler (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - correspondence: vassily Aksyonov (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - information on adoption (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - advocacy day March 20, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - correspondence: Sayeed Ahmad (late 70's early 80's) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - AIDS artical (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Edward Albee (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Alcohol information (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "Born Guilty", clippings, notes, research (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Born Guilty", script, research, notes (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Germany and the Germans, research and video tapes (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - research: Born in the republic of South Africa (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - press release, playbill, notes on "Born Yesterday" (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Bosoms and Neglect", research and notes (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "Bound to Rise", playbill (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "The Boys From Syracuse", playbill and press release (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "Boccaccio", playbill, production and sales info, misc. materials (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "Born Guilty", production book (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Boccaccio", misc. materials (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Bonjour, La Bonjour", review (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "Boris Godounov", script (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "Boesman and Lena", reviews, press releases, etc... (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Bodies", articals (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "baby with the Bathwater" playbill (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "The Bacchae", playbill (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "Bad Habits", playbill (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "Bag Lady", playbill (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - "The Balcony", correspondence, playbill, notes, misc. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "Ballerina", correspondence (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Ballroom", playbill (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "Balm in Guiliad", playbill (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "Balyasnikou", playbill (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - "Banjo dancing", reviews, playbill, notes. etc... (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - "The Barbie Project", playbill (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "The Beaver Coat", review (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - "BeBob", playbill, reviews, etc... (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "Beclch", playbill (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Beckett Plays, misc materials (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - "Becoming Memories", playbill (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - "The Bedbug", playbill (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - "Beehive", playbill (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - "Beggar's opera", playbill (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - "The Belle of Amherst", playbill (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - "Bent", review (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - "Betrayal", 2 playbills (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "Beyond the Fringe", playbill, review (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "Beyond Therapy", misc. materials (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - "Big time Buck White", articals (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - "The Big White Fog", playbills etc... (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "Billy Bishop", play bill (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - "Bingo", artical (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "bio of Max Frisce (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - "The Birthday Party", playbill (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "The Blacks", playbill and correspondence (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "Black Comedy" (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - "The Black Mikado" correspondence (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - "The Baclsmiths Daughter", artical (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "Black terror", playbill and review (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - "The Blood Knot", script (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - "Blood Wedding", script (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - "Bloody Harry", artical (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - "Bloomers", artical (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - "Blue Denim", corespondence (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - "Blues for Mister Charlie", playbill (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - "Blues in the Night", articals (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - "Blue Window", playbill (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - "Boccaccio", script (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - "Boccaccio", script (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - "Boccaccio", script (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - "Boccaccio", script (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - correspondence with Bob Mondello, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - invitation from Walter and Joan Mondale (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Timothy Monich, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - info on the Monk Family (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - correspondence: Benjamin Moore, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - recommendation to NYU for Christina Moore, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - correspondence with Gene Minkow, 1970's-1990 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - correspondence: Honor More, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - correspondence: Arthur Miller, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - correspondence: William Mintzer, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - correspondence: Malcom Morrision, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - notes and transcript for speech to Mount Vernon College, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - correspondence: Gilbert Moses, 1970's-1980's (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - correspondence: Larry Mirkin, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - correspondence: National Arts Stabilization Fund, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - correspondence: Miluakee Rep. Theatre, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - correspondence: Mr. Mirvish, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Natela Muntikova (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - correspondence regarding Yasef Mundy (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - correspondence:Carl Mulert, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Janet Neipris: manuscripts, correspondence and articals (1970's) (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Janet Neipris: cont. (1980's-1990's) (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Neighborhood Playhouse: program (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - info regarding the NY International Festival of the Arts (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - correspondence and info: New Playwright Theatre (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - correspondence: the new harmony project, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - NY Theatre workshop (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - NY Shakespear Festival, Joe Papp (1970's) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - The New York Theatre of Brooklyn, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - The New York Theatre of Brooklyn (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - The New England Theatre Conference, Inc. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - paper with Danny Newman's name on it. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - correspondence: Richard Nelson (late 70's early 80's) (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - NEA - 5 year plan (1983) (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - info on John Frohnmayer (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - NEA - ensemble grant with Zelda's background info (1983) (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - NEA ensamble grant with Zel's background info cont. (1983) (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Artistic Association - NEA (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - National Endownmebt in the Humanities - Joe Duffy (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - National Theatre DC (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - National Theatre conference (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - national town meeting, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - NEA think tank info (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - brochure for the National Theatre of Great Britain (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - general info on a National Theatre (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - correspondence: National Scanning Board, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - NEA grant application for the Musical Director Artisitc Associate, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - NEA grant applications 1985 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - NEA challenge grant, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - notes on NPR spot, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - NEH grant to RSC info (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - National Medal of Arts, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - National Geographic Magazine from January, 1983 with Mention of Zelda and the Arena Stage (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - correspondence: National Committee on Arts for the Handicapped (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - National Corporate Theatre Fund (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - The National Corporate Theatre Fund (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - NBC grant program (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - general info NEA (folder 1 of 5) (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - general info NEA (2 of 5) (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - general info NEA (3 of 5) (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - general info NEA (4 of 5) (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - general info NEA (5 of 5) (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - reel tape: ITP 2-3 one Act Plays (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Reel Tape: ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - news clippings, notes, etc.. (ITP 2-3 One Act Plays) (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - misc materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - "Duck Hunt", script (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - "Dude:The Highway of Life", playbill (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - "The Dumbwaiter" and "The Collection", playbill (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - "The Duplex", playbill (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - "The Slave" and "The Toilet", playbill and correspondence (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - "Dylan", playbill (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - "Eastern Standard", playbill and misc. materials (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - "The Egg", playbill (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - correspondence about "Edward II" (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - correspondence: Edwin Wilson (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - "The Effect of Gamma Rays on the Man in the Moon", playbill (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - correspondence, "East of Jordan" (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - correspondence: "Einstien the Man" (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - "Einstein on the Beach", playbill (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - "Electra" and "The Electronic Niggers and Others", playbill (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - notes on "Elmer Gantry" (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - notes on "Elmer Gantry" (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - notes on "Elmer Gantry" (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - "Elmer Gantry", script (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - notes on "Elmer Gantry" (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - "Electra", playbill, notes and correspondence (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - "Eleanor", playbill (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - "El Grande de Coca Cola", playbill and letter (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - notes on "Elmer Gantry" (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - notes on "Elmer Gantry" (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - notes on "Elmer Gantry" (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - "Emma", playbill (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - program, "Festival of American Classics" at The Emperor Jones (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - "Emigres", production notes (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - "Emigres", misc. notes (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - "Encore Brel", playbill (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - "Endecott and the Red Cross", playbill (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - "Endgame", playbill and reviews (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - "Enemies", misc. notes and playbill (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - "Enemies", programs, notes and reviews (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - "Enemy of the People", correspondence, notes, playbill (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - "Enemy of the People", misc notes (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - "Enemy of the People", notes, research, playbills (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - "Enemy of the People", evlauation of performance (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - "Emeny of the People", script (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - "The Ascent of Mt. Fuji", script (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - "The Ascent of Mt. Fuji", script (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - "The Ascent of Mt. Fuji", correspondence, notes, reviews, press releases (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - "The Ascent of Mt. Fuji", playbills, correspondence, notes (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - "The Ascent of Mt. Fuji", performance evaluation data (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - "The Ascent of Mt. Fuji", script in Russian (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - "The Ascent of Mt. Fuji", corrected script (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - correspondence; Scott Rudin (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - USA/USSR cultural exchange information (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - "Crime and Punishment", script (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - "Crime and Punishment", notes (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - recommendation letters for Andrew Sachs (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - "The Cherry Orchard", notes (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - "Strider", notes (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - "The Scene Shop", notes (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - USA-USSR exchange trip (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - correspondence: University of Wisconsin, Madison (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Notes on a Unnamed play (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - recommendation letters for Albert Schoemann (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - "Two Men", misc. notes and info (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - correspondence from Mary Weiner, ScreenScope Inc. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - misc. materials, ITP 2-3 One Act Plays (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Tony Award congratulation letters, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Tony Award congratulation letters, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Invitation to the 1976 Tony awards, transcript of Zelda's Acceptance speech, articals and misc. materials (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - correspondence: George Touliatos (Box 24, Folder 4)